# Gareth Gomersall

# Front End Developer

After several years working in the financial markets as a Money Broker I started my own online company. This is when I fell in love with coding. In 2015 I successfully completed the General Assembly WDI bootcamp, furthering my knowledge of web design and coding.

me@garethg.com

in linkedin.com/in/ggomersall

twitter.com/GarethG\_

github.com/ggomersall

garethg.com

07585314836

# **Experience:**

#### Front End Developer, MedicAnimal - Jan 01 2017 to current

Within the first year at MedicAnimal I progressed from a Junior Front End Developer to Mid Front End Developer gaining more lead roles on different projects to develop and focus on. Current projects:

- · Lead on implementing redesign of FE for all brands
- Built a Node application that runs MongoDB Geo-Spatial queries on customer data and their closest animal shelter - mapping the queried data to mapbox and exporting it to a CSV file for further investigation by our Business team
- · Investigating the implementation of Elastic search to replace our current Solr integration

The projects that I've worked on, Including last year, are:

- Tech lead for SEO and implementing micro data across the website
- creating a survey poll for customers to vote on marketing generated questions and answers
- · moving our PetMeds brand over to a responsive website
- building a symptom checker for pet advice helping pet owners to initially diagnose their pets illness for vet referrals
- Assisted with the planning and implementation of DPD api for local pickup

#### Junior Developer, MedicAnimal - Jan 27 2016 to Dec 31 2016

This is my first commercial role as a Junior Front-End Developer. The role focuses on implementing new features for the website and fixing existing bugs with in an agile working environment, running on a two week sprint schedule.

This role requires me to work collaboratively with the business and marketing department. Technologies / Languages used include HTML/JSTL, LESS/SASS and Javascript/jQuery, Cloudinary, Continuous Integration, Hybris Platform as well as working closely with the Back-End Developers developing in Java.

#### Part-time Instructor, General Assembly London - April 2016 to current

Part-time instructor for Getting started in Web Development at General Assembly, introducing non developers to the world of coding and web development.

#### GA WDI, London - Sept 28 2015 to Dec 18 2015

WDI is a three month bootcamp focusing on teaching their students numerous web technologies while preparing students to become Junior Web Developers working within an agile environment. The technologies that I learnt were: HTML/HAML, CSS/SASS, Ruby on Rails, Sinatra, Node.js, jQuery, JavaScript, AngularJS, SQL, PostgreSQL, MongoDB, TDD, Heroku, AWS, Git and working with third party API's.

# **Experience Continued:**

#### Money Broker - ICAP PLC - Nov 2007 to May 2012

I started working on the EURO FX desk as a Junior Money Broker supporting the Senior Brokers with voice and electronic deals, deal ticket entry, trading deals with external brokers and other worldwide ICAP trading desks.

My role evolved to moving to the Emerging Market desk, trading in Hungarian and Romanian FX.

In 2011 I moved to ICAP Bahrain to trade in Middle Eastern FX currencies and SPOT, dealing with clients from Saudi Arabia, Bahrain, Kuwait, Dubai and Qatar.

#### Desktop Support - ICAP PLC - April 2006 to Nov 2007

The role at ICAP as Desktop Support was to support all front office brokers and back office support staff in their day to day IT issues. The support covered Microsoft products, various Money Broking tools and software and printers and hardware issues.

I was the Lead Engineer on maintaining and supporting the users mobile devices i.e. rollouts, troubleshooting, technical issues and liaising with third party vendors.

During my post I was elected as the Lead Support Engineer to our Copenhagen office.

### Skills:

CSS		Node.js	••000	Mongo DB	•••00
HTML		JavaScript	•••00	React	••000
Ruby on Rails	•••00	JQuery	•••00	AngularJS	••000

## **Education:**

High school - St Albans College, South Africa, 1998

Web Development Immersive - General Assembly, London, Sept 2015 - Dec 2015

## More About Me:

After moving to the UK in 1998 i've been bitten by the travel bug, I enjoy exploring new countries and experiencing new cultures.

As well as this I'm considered a bit of a geek by my friends and loved ones as I get far too excited about all things tech, and enjoy learning new languages.

## Things I Love:

